Guide to the Experiment Station Publications Photographic Collection 1949-1979
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Experiment Station Publications Photographic Collection
1949-1979
1950-1970
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
P 132
Oregon State University. Agricultural Experiment Station.
0.3 cubic foot, including 500 photographs 1 box
The Experiment Station Publications Photographic Collection document Agricultural Experiment Station research in Corvallis and at Branch Stations throughout Oregon.
This collection consists of photographs of Station research both in Corvallis and at Branch Stations throughout Oregon. Subjects include Station personnel; Branch station and campus buildings and research facilities; and research projects in agricultural chemistry, agricultural engineering, animal sciences, dairy husbandry, entomology, crop and soil science, fisheries and wildlife, food technology, horticulture, irrigation, microbiology, nutrition, poultry science, and vegetable crops.
Many of the photographs were taken by Robert Birdsall, Agricultural Information Specialist (1952-1963) and later Journalism Department faculty (1963-1983). Other photographers include Bob Mason, Bill Reasons, and Len Calvert.
This collection consists almost exclusively of b/w contact prints and camera negatives (4x5 and 120). The contact prints are glued to 6x9 in. cards. There are also a few b/w 8x10 prints without camera negatives (P132:237-238) and several color prints and negatives (P132:239-241). One negative (P132:054) has been removed from the collection because of excessive buckling of the emulsion.
All of the images have been assigned individual item numbers (P132:1-P132:241). The bulk of the images are grouped by general subject as shown on the inventory.
Collection is open for research.
Many other photographs of Agricultural Experiment Station programs are part of the Agricultural Experiment Station (P 29), Agricultural Communications (P 120), and Station Bulletin Illustrations (P 19) Photographic Collections.
Birdsall, Robert Hill; Calvert, Leonard; Reasons, Bill
Oregon State College. Agricultural Experiment Station
Agricultural experiment stations--Oregon; Agriculture--Research--Oregon; Agricultural chemistry--Oregon; Agricultural engineering--Oregon; Crops--Research--Oregon; Entomology--Research--Oregon; Fisheries--Research--Oregon; Irrigation--Research--Oregon; Microbiology--Research--Oregon; Poultry--Research--Oregon
Photographic prints; Film negatives
Agriculture; Colleges and Universities; Fisheries and Wildlife; Science; Water and Water Rights; Oregon; Corvallis; Photographs
- Statistical Science
  - OSU IBM 1620 located in statistical services computer laboratory, July 1961; P132:001-P132:003 (Box 1)
    Negative 1837E-1839E
- Buildings
  - Exterior and second floor of Waldo Hall, June 1970; P132:004 (Box 1)
    Negative 0076E
  - New Bio-Science building (Nash Hall) and Dr. Paul R. Elliker, P132:005; color (Box 1)
    [negative 849E]
- Personnel
  - Dr. Spencer Apple and Dr. William Frazier viewing research bean crop at Mid Willamette Experiment Station, Nov 9, 1970; P132:006-P132:007 (Box 1)
    Negative 00066E and 00055E
  - Retirement party for Frank L. Ballard (left). Also Mrs. Ballard, Dean and Mrs. Price; taken by Robert Birdsall, June 1961; P132:008 (Box 1)
    Negative 1758E
  - Mercury team Dr. Donald R. Buhler and Dr. Robert R. Claeys, Aug 1970; P132:009-P132:010 (Box 1)
    Negative 815E
  - Len Calvert, Extension information specialist, c 1970; P132:011 (Box 1)
    Negative 00769
  - Statistician Lyle D. Calvin uses a computer for processing fish survey data, winter 1969; P132:012 (Box 1)
    Negative 00186E
  - Ted H. Carlson, associate professor of journalism, office in Waldo Hall, June 1970; P132:013 (Box 1)
    Negative 00759E
  - Horace B. Cheney, Soils department head, and soil scientist Larry Alban; taken by R. Birdsall, 1955; P132:014 (Box 1)
    Negative 1635E
  - OSU animal scientist David C. Church checks liquors fermenting in an artificial rumen, Spring 1963; P132:015 (Box 1)
    Negative 1998E
  - Superintendent Thomas P. Davidson, Umatilla Experiment Station, June 1970; P132:016 (Box 1)
    Negative 00764E
  - Joyce Driscoll, Dec 1970; P132:017 (Box 1)
    Negative 00176E
  - Dr. Harold Evans and graduate student viewing an experiment involving cobalt nitrogen fixation, Nov 10, 1970; P132:018 (Box 1)
    Negative 00060E
  - Carl L. Foster, Squaw Butte Field Day, Sept 22, 1970; P132:019 (Box 1)
    Negative 00083E
  - Dr. Robert W. Henderson, Assistant Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station, no date; P132:020 (Box 1)
    Negative 940E
  - Dr. Robert W. Henderson, Assistant Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station, shown swiping ripe blueberries from the Lewis Brown farm, no date; P132:021 (Box 1)
    Negative 911E
  - Dr. Robert W. Henderson, Assistant Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station, no date; P132:022-P132:023 (Box 1)
    Negative 854E and 975E
  - Elbert N. Hoffman, Superintendent, Malheur Experiment Station, June 22-26, 1970; P132:024 (Box 1)
    Negative 00141E
  - Dr. Harold J. Jensen, nematologist, examines specimen in his laboratory, 1950s; P132:025-P132:026 (Box 1)
    Negative 385E-386E
  - Dr. James A.B. McArthur, Superintendent, Eastern Oregon Experiment Station, June 22-26, 1970; P132:027 (Box 1)
    Negative 00167E
  - David P. Moore, Department of Soils, 1972 and pre-1970; P132:028-P132:029 (Box 1)
    Negative 34E
  - Mrs. Olive Mott, Summit, measures daily rainfall for U.S. Weather Bureau, 1950s; P132:030 (Box 1)
    Negative 1092E
  - Jim Oldfield, OSC animal husbandman, checks weight of lambs on antibiotic supplement feeding, Jan 1957; P132:031 (Box 1)
    Negative 1475E
  - Al Oliver; taken by R. Birdsall, June 1961; P132:032 (Box 1)
    Negative 1759E
  - F.E. Price, Dean and Director of Agriculture, 1950s; P132:033-P132:035 (Box 1)
    Negative 1095E-1097E
  - Dean Price presenting 1961 Basic Research award to Jim Oldfield, O. Herbert Muth, John R. Schubert, Jan 1962; P132:036 (Box 1)
    Negative 1847E
  - Robert J. Raleigh, Squaw Butte Superintendent at Squaw Butte Field Day, Sept 22, 1970; P132:037-P132:039 (Box 1)
    Negative 00091E
  - Larry Rittenhouse, Squaw Butte Field Day, Sept 22, 1970; P132:040-P132:041 (Box 1)
    Negative 00088E
  - Charles Sanderson, former assistant editor, Experiment Station, 1970; P132:042 (Box 1)
    Negative 00728E
  - Forrest A. Sneva, Squaw Butte Field Day, Sept 22, 1970; P132:043 (Box 1)
    Negative 00087E
  - Harley A. Turner, Squaw Butte Field Day, Sept 22, 1970; P132:044-P132:046 (Box 1)
    Negative 00095E
  - Dr. George F. Waldo looks over a bench of 2172 strawberry plants, 1950s; P132:047 (Box 1)
    Negative 931E
  - Howard Wight engaged in starling experiment, no date; P132:048 (Box 1)
    Negative 00058E
  - G. Burton Wood with Art Sawyer, ex-Branch. Supt., rancher C. Miller and Extension Agent Ray Novtny, Nov 23, 1970; P132:049 (Box 1)
    Negative 00096E
  - G. Burton Wood and Robert J. Raleigh, Squaw Butte Superintendent at Squaw Butte Field Day, Sept 22, 1970; P132:050 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Arthur S. Wu, Asst. Prof. of Animal Physiology, June 1970; P132:051-P132:053 (Box 1)
    Negative 874E
  - Dr. Roy Young, associate plant pathologist, examines potato plant, 1950s; P132:054 (Box 1)
    Negative 472E removed from collection due to excessive buckling of the emulsion.
- Agricultural Engineering
  - Glen Page, OSC agricultural engineer, examines new soil fumigation blade he developed, Oct 1956; P132:055 (Box 1)
    Negative 1294E
  - Kink pipe before Dale Kirk, Agricultural Engineer, applies water pressure from hydraulic pump, 1950s; P132:056 (Box 1)
    Negative 876E
  - Te May Ching at work in seed lab; taken by Len Calvert, Fall 1963; P132:057 (Box 1)
    Negative 2060E
  - Experimental model: machine using vibration to achieve partial separation of seed samples. From left: Byron Mikkelson, Assistant in Ag. Engineering; Dr. Oren Justice, research botanist in Field Crops and Animal Science branch; and Ed Hardin, seed technologist; taken by Calvert, July 1963; P132:058 (Box 1)
    Negative 1955E
  - D.E. Booster, OSC Agricultural Engineer, demonstrating electrostatic seed separator that employs differences in conductivity of seeds as a basis for separation; taken by R. Birdsall, July 1958; P132:059 (Box 1)
    Negative 1666E
  - Gladiolus harvester developed by Myron Cropsey, 1950s; P132:060 (Box 1)
    Negative 954E
  - Gladiolus harvester developed by Myron Cropsey, 1950s; P132:061 (Box 1)
    Negative 957E
  - Cutting daily green chop for dairy feed, 1950s; P132:062 (Box 1)
    Negative 23E
  - Picking pears from a mechanical self-propelled "Girette"near Medford. Hoist arm is controlled from the picker's tower and swings from tree to unloading station where bag is dumped; taken by Don Langmo, 1962; P132:063 (Box 1)
    Negative 1910E
  - Experimental blackberry harvester being tested in Marion county; taken by Birdsall, no date; P132:064 (Box 1)
    Negative 1985E
  - Fence building at the Henry Klages farm, Joseph, Oregon, July 1961; P132:065 (Box 1)
    Negative 1885E
- Branch Stations
  - Ranchers listen to station personnel explain range management programs at Squaw Butte Experiment Station, Nov 24, 1970; P132:066 (Box 1)
    Negative 00077E
  - Robert J. Raleigh begins field day by explaining program, Nov 24, 1970; P132:067 (Box 1)
    Negative 00078E
  - Squaw Butte and station building of Squaw Butte Experiment Station, June 1970; P132:068 (Box 1)
    Negative 00758E
  - Various views of Squaw Butte. Some showing improved range, others showing station herd grazing, summer 1960; P132:069 (Box 1)
    Negative 1723E
  - View of Squaw Butte range, no date; P132:070 (Box 1)
    Negative 884E
  - Burns Post Office (headquarters of Squaw Butte Experiment Station), June 22-26, 1970; P132:071 (Box 1)
    Negative 00067E
  - Experimental greenhouse, plastic, under trial at North Willamette Experiment Station at Aurora; taken by Bob Mason, June 1961; P132:072 (Box 1)
    Negative 1780E
  - Field Day, Umatilla Branch Station, circa 1960; P132:073 (Box 1)
    Print and negative missing, Oct. 1994
  - Harold White, Superintendent of Southern Oregon Branch Station, examines certified talent alfalfa being grown in tent. Seed is from pure stock of talent alfalfa. The tent is used to maintain purity, no date; P132:074 (Box 1)
    Negative 922E
  - Art Sawyer, Superintendent, examines crested wheat grass seedings at Squaw Butte-Harney Branch Station, no date; P132:075 (Box 1)
    Negative 1045E
  - Merril Oveson, Superintendent of Pendleton Branch Station, examines safflower on the station grounds, no date; P132:076 (Box 1)
    Negative 1048E
  - Malheur branch experiment station visitors watch Albert S. Hunter, OSC soils scientist, demonstrate combine designed to harvest experimental grain plots; taken by R. Birdsall, July 1954; P132:077 (Box 1)
    Negative 817E
  - Malcom Johnson, Superintendent of Central Oregon Experiment Station, no date; P132:078-P132:079 (Box 1)
    Negative 1326E
  - Gene Cross tells about research on barley and wheat plots at the station. The woman is the county commissioner, Sept 1970; P132:080-P132:081 (Box 1)
    Negative 18E
  - Superintendent Charles Rohde of the Pendleton Experiment Station, June 1970; P132:082-P132:083 (Box 1)
    Negative 839E
  - Fred Hagelstein (left) talks with Superintendent Charles Rohde. In background is G.Burton Wood, June 1970; P132:084 (Box 1)
  - G. Burton Wood talks with resident before outdoor meeting on lawn of station, June 1970; P132:085-P132:086 (Box 1)
  - Box lunches keep Chamber of Commerce group busy during tour of station facilities, June 1970; P132:087 (Box 1)
  - M.W. Mellenthin with limb cage developed to control temperature, June 1970; P132:088 (Box 1)
    Negative 864E
  - Administration building at Station, June 1970; P132:089 (Box 1)
  - Walt Mellenthin, Superintendent, June 1970; P132:090 (Box 1)
  - Field Day at North Willamette branch station; taken by Birdsall, 1960; P132:091 (Box 1)
    Negative 1953E
  - Pear breeding experiments at the Southern Oregon Branch Experiment Station are aimed at improving pear varieties. A tree has been completely covered to insure controlled breeding work. Seedling produced from see on this tree are resistant to blight and make excellent rootstocks. Bees are kept in enclosure for pollinating. They transfer pollen from a bouquet of flowers of another variety, Summer 1950; P132:092 (Box 1)
    Negative 321E
  - General shot of beef feeding lots at Umatilla branch station; taken by Birdsall, Sept 1962; P132:093 (Box 1)
    Negative 1961E
- Vegetable Crops
  - William Allan Frazier, horticulturist, examines blue lake type bush beans he has developed; taken by Mason, Sept 1956; P132:094 (Box 1)
    Negative 1467E
  - William Allan Frazier, horticulturist, examines blue lake pole bean parent he is using in genetic work; taken by Mason, Sept 1956; P132:095 (Box 1)
    Negative 1470E
  - William Allan Frazier, horticulturist, developed high quality bush bean through eight backcrosses to famed Blue Lake pole bean. Result: tender, stringless pods yielding 4 to 5 tons per acre and well-adapted to machine picking; taken by R. Birdsall, 1958; P132:096 (Box 1)
    Negative 1689E
  - William Allan Frazier, horticulturist, examines early hybrid tomatoes on left, compared with Stokesdales on right, no date; P132:097 (Box 1)
    Negative 980E
  - Mechanical harvesting on Wiley Clowers farm. Potatoes on ground are undersized taken out by eliminators, Nov 1960; P132:098 (Box 1)
    Negative 1784E
  - Mechanical transfer from sacks to bulk-bed on Harold Allen farm, Nov 1960; P132:099a (Box 1)
    Negative 10E
  - Close-up of mechanical harvester, Nov 1960; P132:099b (Box 1)
  - Digger and harvester working together, Nov 1960; P132:099c (Box 1)
  - Mechanical bush bean harvester covers 3 1/2 to 5 acres a day, travels between three-fourths to one mile an hour, and picks 15 to 20 tons a day. Tested this year by Oregon State College, the machine proved 70 to 85 percent efficient in harvesting new Blue Lake hybrid bush beans on OSC experimental plots near Corvallis; taken by R. Birdsall, 1958; P132:100 (Box 1)
    Negative 1687E
  - Mechanical harvester being tested on onions in Malheur County, Fall 1961; P132:101 (Box 1)
    Negative 1862E
  - Propane burning of potato vines for easier harvest and for Verticillium Wilt control at Harold Allen farm, Nov 1960; P132:102 (Box 1)
    Negative 19E
- Landscapes
  - View of Harvey Aluminum plant, The Dalles, 1961; P132:103 (Box 1)
    Negative 1863E
  - Entering the Fort Rock Valley form the south, Nov 1955; P132:104 (Box 1)
    Negative 1219E
  - Snow drifts in the Fort Rock Valley, Nov 1955; P132:105 (Box 1)
    Negative 1218E
  - View of Fort Rock by way of Rube Long's mail box, Nov 1955; P132:106 (Box 1)
    Negative 1207E
  - Typical view of Fort Rock area, Nov 1955; P132:107 (Box 1)
    Negative 1209E
  - View of Hood River Valley from Mid-Columbia Branch Station, 1950s; P132:108 (Box 1)
    Negative 106E
  - View of John Day valley from U.S. Highway 395 between John Day and Pendleton, 1950s; P132:109 (Box 1)
    Negative 1376E
  - Band belonging to Ralph Longfellow is on a long journey from the Snake River to summer range in the high Wallowas, Joseph, Oregon; taken by Walter W. Klages, July 1961; P132:110 (Box 1)
    Negative 1884E
  - View of Harney valley from the foot hills of Steen's Mountain, 1960s; P132:111-P132:112 (Box 1)
    Negative 1239E and Negative 1237E
- Entomology
  - Entomologist William P. Nagel examines sample of damaged bark. Damage inflicted by the Douglas-fir beetle, Spring 1968; P132:113 (Box 1)
    Negative 00204E
  - Peter Westigard, entomologist, check codling moth trap to determine population in test block of pears, 1967-1968; P132:114 (Box 1)
    Negative 00222E
  - OSU entomologist Knud Swenson examines artificially reared aphid colonies, Fall 1963; P132:115 (Box 1)
    Negative 2011E
  - As a marked bee leaves the feeding station, Dr. Edward Anderson, an entomologist from Eastern Oregon College, calls Schricker by walkie talkie and punches his stop watch. Wind direction and velocity are read from the anometer shown at left. Wind is figured to compute the air distance travelled by the bee; taken by Don Wright, Aug 1965; P132:116 (Box 1)
    Negative 2056E
  - Dr. Schricker clocks the bee's return trip to a specially built observational hive. Progressively higher doses of the insecticide, parathion, slows the bee's normal flying speed of above 20 m.p.h. and disrupts an intricate dance which the bees use to communicate distance and direction to food; taken by Don Wright, Aug 1965; P132:117 (Box 1)
    Negative 2057E
  - A honey bee lands at a feeding station to take on a load of sugar solution containing a trace of insecticide. As she sucks up the artificial nectar she will be marked with colored dots to allow the scientists to observe her behavior back at the hive; taken by Don Wright, Aug 1965; P132:118 (Box 1)
    Negative 2055E
  - Station for leafcutter bees at Malheur station; taken by Birdsall, Summer 1963; P132:119 (Box 1)
    Negative 1930E
  - Portable bed for alkali bees at Malheur station; taken by Birdsall, Summer 1963; P132:120 (Box 1)
    Negative 1932E
  - Close up of a bee hive; taken by Stephens, June 1956; P132:121 (Box 1)
    Negative 1366E
  - Earl Brown, county agent at Milton-Freewater spraying cattle with DDT; taken by Goulding, October 1957; P132:122 (Box 1)
    Negative 1655E
  - Backrubbers for insecticide applications for cattle; taken by Goulding, October 1957; P132:123 (Box 1)
    Negative 1656E
  - "Pour-on" treatments can be used either for a single steer or in a sarge feedlot/cattle-grub control, Fall 1963; P132:124 (Box 1)
    Negative 2012E
- Food Technology
  - Dr. Harold Schultz, head of Food Technology at OSC, examines some dehydrated potatoes at the OSC Food Technology lab, 1960s; P132:125 (Box 1)
    Negative 1091E
  - Dr. Harold Schultz examines some hamburger that has been irradiated to kill all bacteria. Cans are stored at 100 degree rooms to test storage quality, 1960s; P132:126 (Box 1)
    Negative 1090E
  - Dr. Robert F.Cain putting ground hamburger into cans before being sent for irradiation, 1960s; P132:127 (Box 1)
    Negative 1161E
  - Dr. Wiegand, left, and Dr. Thomas Onsdorff, right, examine dehydrated onion rings, 1960s; P132:128 (Box 1)
    Negative 1093E
  - Processing blue lake beans at Blue Lake Packers, Corvallis, Fall 1961; P132:129-P132:131 (Box 1)
    Negative 1848E and 1867E-1868E
- Microbiology
  - Roy Wilfred Stein and Paul R. Elliker remove raw milk samples from incubator and will next test them for numbers of bacteria, 1960s; P132:132 (Box 1)
    Negative 1679E
  - Roy Wilfred Stein and William E. Sandine, junior bacteriologist, transfer raw milk to a petri dish where milk will be sealed and incubated, 1960s; P132:133 (Box 1)
    Negative 1678E
- Agricultural Chemistry
  - Paul Weswig with samples of wafered, pelleted, and chopped hay to be tested for carotene following storage; taken by Birdsall, c 1962; P132:134 (Box 1)
    Negative 1982E
  - Virgil Freed, OSC agricultural chemist, measures the surface tension of an experiment spray solution with a tensiometer. Tensiometer is used to measure effectiveness of various wetting agents mixed with chemical sprays; taken by Mason, Mar 1957; P132:135 (Box 1)
    Negative 1503E
  - Agricultural chemist, Virgil Freed, seeking ways to utilize wastes, no date; P132:136 (Box 1)
    Negative 00184E
  - Dr. Joseph Butts, head of Agricultural Chemistry, adjusts the high vacuum system used to make materials radioactive, 1950s; P132:137 (Box 1)
    Negative 432E
  - Using radioactive materials in fundamental research with corn pollination are J. Ritchie Cowan, assistant agronomist (left), and Dr. J.S. Butts, biochemist in charge, 1950s; P132:138 (Box 1)
    Negative 45E
- Poultry Science
  - White leghorn rooster which genetically carries disease resistance plus high egg production. Part of Paul Bernier's survival flock; taken by Reasons, June 1956; P132:139 (Box 1)
    Negative 1410E
  - Rooster-hen ratio requirements are being studied at the college. This pen of birds is being used in the trials. As few as 6 or 7 roosters per 100 hens have been found satisfactory for consistent high fertility, Aug 1950; P132:140 (Box 1)
    Negative 265E
  - Effect of unidentified nutrients, probably vitamins, on chick growth is shown here. Chick at right has been fed normal growing diet supplemented with dried egg yolk. Chick at left has been fed only usual diet; taken by Mason, June 1957; P132:141 (Box 1)
    Negative 1499E
  - One of 200 white leghorn families used in selecting disease resistant birds. Part of Paul Bernier's experimental survival flock; taken by Bill Reasons, June 1956; P132:142 (Box 1)
    Negative 1411E
  - The value of "open-air" poultry houses is being studied by the Experiment Station. They show real promise for the Willamette Valley in early trials, Apr 1949; P132:143 (Box 1)
    Negative 9E
  - Dr. Paul E. Bernier demonstrates measurement techniques used in chicken breeding research, Aug 1950; P132:144 (Box 1)
    Negative 264E
  - Tom turkey at the OSC experimental turkey farm, Oct 26, 1951; P132:145 (Box 1)
    Negative 667E
  - View of OSC turkey flock; taken by Bill Reasons, Nov 1956; P132:146-P132:148 (Box 1)
    Negative 1327E, 1321E, and 1325E
  - Cornelius Bateson and Praetum broiler, 1950s; P132:149 (Box 1)
    Negative 1264E
  - Tests on hatchability. Newly hatched tray of chicks held by Ben Kladder (Dryden Hall janitor and maintenance person, especially boiler room maintenance), June 1951; P132:150 (Box 1)
    Negative 620E
  - Dr. J.E. Parker and rooster with dubbed comb, no date; P132:151 (Box 1)
    Negative 390E
  - George Arscott shown weighing broilers fed high energy rations, 1950s; P132:152 (Box 1)
    Negative 1269E
  - George Arscott examines broilers fed comparative ration of Oregon (right) or Midwest corn, 1950s; P132:153 (Box 1)
    Negative 126E
  - Dr. Paul Bernier, OSC poultry researcher, examines hybrid rooster containing lethal gene, no date; P132:154 (Box 1)
    Negative 1001E
  - Dr. Paul Bernier holding roosters developed by two hybrid lines. White leghorn at left has lethal gene and its chicks will never live if sired by this rooster. Normal rooster is on right, no date; P132:155 (Box 1)
    Negative 1000E
  - Dr. Paul Bernier examines white leghorn rooster which genetically carries disease resistance plus high egg production; taken by Bill Reasons, June 1956; P132:156 (Box 1)
    Negative 1412E
  - Dr. Paul Bernier examines hen from one of his survival flock experiments; taken by Bill Reasons, June 1956; P132:157 (Box 1)
    Negative 1409E
- Dairy Husbandry
  - Making cheese at the OSC dairy plant, 1960s; P132:158 (Box 1)
    Negative 871E
  - Making butter at the OSC dairy plant, 1960s; P132:159 (Box 1)
    Negative 869E
  - View of OSC dairy barn, 1950s; P132:160 (Box 1)
    Negative 1071E
- Fisheries and Wildlife
  - Student examining trap for insects, algae, etc. located in Berry Creek. Picture used for cover of "Oregon's Agricultural Progress," winter issue, 1960, Dec 1959; P132:161 (Box 1)
    Negative 1693E
  - Student using dip net in Berry Creek, an experimental 2creek located on Adair tract, Dec 1959; P132:162 (Box 1)
    Negative 1694E
  - Beet juice being dumped into Willamette River near Eugene; taken by Bill Reasons, 1959; P132:163 (Box 1)
    Negative 1696E